Finding Aid for the Alfred Leonard and Joseph Leonard Collection PASC-M.0180
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alfred Leonard and Joseph Leonard collection
1902-2001
UCLA Library Special Collections
PASC-M.0180
18 Linear Feet (36 boxes)
This collection documents the musical activities and compositions of the brothers Alfred and Joseph Leonard.
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Eleanor Rubin, 1999, 2000.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942348563606533
Biography
P. (Peter) Alfred Leonard (ne Alfred Levi; b. Mannheim, Germany 1909; d. September 10, 1988) was an entrepreneur, director of symphonic programs on KFAC, radio host for The Golden Hour in 1935 for which he also published several monographs for subscribers, owner of a Los Angeles music store, Gateway to Music (1939-1958), founder of the Los Angeles Music Guild (1944) and director of its concert series (1945-1952). His family was originally from Mannheim, and he came to the United States in 1933. As an avid supporter of classical music, his circle of friends included Ernst and Lilly Toch (also from Mannheim), Artur Schnabel, piano duo performers Vitya Vronsky and Victor Babin, among others whose concerts he sponsored and careers he followed such as Joseph Szigeti, and Otto Klemperer. His relationship with the Tochs was very close, and correspondence included exchanges of gifts, poetry, and musical manuscripts. As Ernst shared the same birthday as Alfred's daughter, Barbara, for several years he sent musical compositions and a theme and variations based on her name in celebration of their joint birthday. Alfred was also a writer; this collection includes his articles published in magazines and a collection of essays, and other unpublished writings and lectures. He published Gateway to Music - Bulletin (1939-1952) as an adjunct to his store with reviews of recordings. As the host to the radio show, he also kept reel to reel recordings of his shows, and maintained recordings of Music Guild concert performances.
His brother Joseph Julius Leonard (ne Josef Julius Levi) (b. August 7, 1903; Mannheim, Germany d. May 20, 1979) was a blind, talented pianist and organist, who had an extensive performing career in Germany before immigrating to the United States. In 1936 he was invited by Manuel Compinksy to join the faculty at the Pacific Institute of Music and Fine Arts, where he served on the faculty. In Los Angeles, he served as organist and choir director at Beth Am synagogue (1953-?) and performed in secular and religious concerts as a soloist and choir director.
This collection provides valuable documents on Los Angeles Western classical musical programs, local Jewish community musical events, Toch materials not found in other collections, German and German Jewish newspapers from the 1920s-30s, and correspondence with important composers and performers. In addition, this collection provides supporting material on the lives of Ernst Toch, Artur Schnabel, Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, piano duo Vitya Vronsky and Victor Babin, and Joseph Szigeti.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of documents, clippings, music programs, brochures, correspondence, recordings and photographs relating to the careers of Alfred and Joseph Leonard. Correspondence includes communications with Artur Schnabel, Ernst and Lilly Toch, pianists Babin-Vronksy, Joseph Szigeti, Peter Heyworth, and others. Collection also includes other printed publications, monographs, German language newspapers from 1920s and 30s, musical compositions and manuscripts by Ernst Toch and Joseph Leonard. Recordings include published and unpublished 33, 45 and 78 rpm records, reel-to-reel audiotapes, CD transfers of 78s.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Sheet music - Published
Sheet music - Unpublished manuscripts
Correspondence
Newspapers, Newsletters, Magazines
Clippings, Advertisements, Reviews
Books and Monographs
Articles, Lectures, Sermons, Other Writings
Scrap books
Music Programs
Documents
Catalogues and Brochures
Photographs
Sound recordings
Music -- Manuscripts.; Music -- California -- Los Angeles.; Leonard, Alfred; Leonard, Joseph; Schnabel, Artur; Toch, Ernst
- Sheet music - Published, Series I.
  - Heyer, O. Oscar Wilde - Jolly Utter Gallop. 5 p. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Piano score. Published by Oliver Ditson and Co.
  - [German songs arranged for violin]. 16 p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    In cover labelled in pencil "Old German Songs". 2 sets; second set contains only pp. 1-4; 13-16.
  - Nevin, Ethelbert. Melody and Habanera for violin and piano. 7 p. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    "J. Gold[?]' in pencil upper right hand corner of cover. Violin part and piano score.
  - Vivaldi, Antonio. Concerti delle Stagioni - I. La Primavera. 19 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Score. Contains pencilled in dynamics, bowings, and directions.
  - Vivaldi, Antonio. Concerti delle Stagioni - II. L'Estate. 24 p. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Vivaldi, Antonio. Concerti delle Stagioni - III. L'Autunno. 23 p. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Vivaldi, Antonio. Concerti delle Stagioni - IV. L'Inverno. 20 p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Toch, Ernst. The Princess and the Pea. 75 p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Piano score. 2 copies.
  - Toch, Ernst. Geographical Fugue for Speaking Chorus. 13 p. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    2 copies of score; handwritten note attached to second copy "Abby Singers album and title: - 5 centuries of song Decca Records".
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian. Piano Concerto in F minor. 28 p. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Eulenberg edition with foreword by Arnold Schering.
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian. Concerto in F minor for piano and orchestra. 28 p. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Published by International Music Company.
  - Toch, Ernst. Pinocchio. 30 p. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Miniature score published by Associated Music Publishers, Inc.
  - Toch, Ernst. Peter Pan Opus 76. 171 p. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Edition Schott 4582.
  - Kreisler, Fritz. Viennese Popular Song. 2 p. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Violin part.
  - Schubert, Franz. [German songs arranged for violin]. 8 p. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Violin part. Song titles include: Standchen; Ave Maria; Aufenthalt; Der Neugierige; Lob der Thranen; Am Meer; Du bist die Ruh; Ungelduld; Morgengrussl Gretchen am Spinnrade; Sei mir gegrusst; Der Wanderer.
  - Collection of Pieces for Violin and Piano Volume 3. 74 p. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Piano score.
  - [4 unidentified piano pieces]. negative; photostat copies; 5 p. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Toch, Ernst. Vorspiel zu einem Marchen (Der Pinzessin auf der Erbse). 8 p. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Toch, Ernst. Valse. 23 p. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Score for mixed speaking chorus and optional percussion.
  - Kolodin, Irving; Braunstein, Dr. Joseph. Liner notes to 32 Sonatas - Beethoven Society Edition. 12 p. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Liner notes part of Limited Beethoven Society Edition contains boxed set with volume 1 of 32 sonatas (sheet music); liner notes on recordings; 13 rpm records of performances by Artur Schnabel. See remainder of box of box 8 for 33 rpm records; volume 1 and volume 2 of sheet music. Original box discarded due to mold.
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van. 32 Sonatas for the Pianoforte edited by Artur Schnabel Volume 1. 411 p. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Volume 1 of sheet music part of Limited Beethoven Society Edition contains boxed set with volume 1 of 32 sonatas (sheet music); liner notes on recordings; 13 rpm records of performances by Artur Schnabel. Editor's preface contains handwritten dedication in German to Josef Levi [Leonard] from Artur Schnabel dated April 24, 1939. See remainder of box 8 for liner notes; 13 rpm record set and volume 2 of sheet music. Original box discarded due to mold.
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van. 32 Sonatas for the pianoforte edited by Artur Schnabel Volume 2. 451 p. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Volume 2 of sheet music possibly part of Limited Beethoven Society Edition. Boxed set contained volume 1 of 32 sonatas (sheet music); liner notes on recordings; 13 rpm records of performances by Artur Schnabel. See remainder of box 8 for liner notes; 13 rpm records and volume 1 of sheet music. Original box discarded due to mold.
- Sheet music - Unpublished manuscripts, Series II.
  - Music by Joseph Leonard, Subseries 1.
    - Leonard, Joseph L. Three Little Pieces. ms; xerox; 10 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Original and 2 xerox copies of compositions. Transcribed from braille by Sarah I. French. Titles of compostions: A Little March; Album Leaf; A Little Dance. 2nd xerox copy contains fingerings and directions in pencil.
    - Leonard, Joseph L. Lullaby (Bagatelle). ms; xerox; 5 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Dedication on cover: "To my two twin nieces. September 8, 1940." Xerox of page 2 incomplete.
    - Leonard, Joseph L. [Composition notebook]. ms; 20 p. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Title on cover: "Kompositionen Josef Levi 1.1.1924." Titles include: Praludium 1; Menuett; Wiegenleid; Albumblatt; Freudvoll und leidvoll; Die Rache.
    - Leonard, Joseph L. Festival Hymn. ozalid; 7 p. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Note under title: "Text taken from inscription on the altar of Temple Beth Am"; "Based on an old melody".
    - Leonard, Joseph L. Ode to Youth for Mixed Voices - A capella. ozalid; 9 p. (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Poem and music by Joseph Leonard. 9 copies. note under title "A graduation gift to my nieces".
    - Leonard, Joseph L. Ode to Youth for Mixed Voices - A capella. spiral-bound ozalid. (Box 2, Folder 7)
      9 copies of poem and music by Joseph Leonard. Note under title: "A graduation gift to my nieces".
    - Leonard, Joseph L. Chor - Lied am Chanukah. 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 8)
      42 copies. Composer's name written as Josef Levi.
    - Leonard, Joseph L. Un 'Sane Tokef. ozalid; 8 p. (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Dedicated to Cantor Abraham Salkov and the Temple Choir.
    - Leonard, Joseph L. V'sham'ru (Canon). ozalid; 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Leonard, Joseph L. Sholom Aleychem. ozalid; 10 p. (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Song by I. Goldfarb; arranged for vocal duet with piano accompaniment by Joseph Leonard. 2 copies, each with different cover.
    - Leonard, Joseph L. Psalm 130. ozalid; 8 p. (Box 2, Folder 12)
      For soprano solo and organ. Dedicated to Kean Mantius in friendship.
    - Leonard, Joseph L. Tsadik Katomor (Psalm 92, 12-15). ozalid; 4 p. (Box 2, Folder 13)
      "Newly revised and dedicated to the Choir of Temple Beth Am". 2 versions.
    - Leonard, Joseph L. May the Words of My Mouth. ozalid; 3 p. (Box 2, Folder 14)
      "To my very dear friend Erna Stone". 2 copies.
    - Leonard, Joseph L. V'shom'ru. ozalid; 5 p. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      "To his friend Abraham Salkov".
    - Leonard, Joseph L. Ashre for Slichoth. ms; 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Scored for cantor and choir.
    - Leonard, Joseph. Silent Devotion. ozalid; 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Leonard, Joseph. Silent Devotion for Friday Evening. ozalid; 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 18)
      "To Marianne Kolben in friendship". Copyist M. M. J. 2 copies.
    - Leonard, Joseph. The Sabbath Day. ozalid; 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      "To my dear ones." Text by Judah Halevi(?).
    - Leonard, Joseph. A Little Dance. ms; 4 p. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Transcribed by Viktor Babin. Letter enclosed with ms from Babin to Alfred. Babin explains that the piece was more complex than first appeared and thus new transcription was necessary; that the composition merits publication.
    - Leonard, Joseph. Yih'yu L'rotson. xerox; 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      2 copies.
    - Leonard, Joseph. Sonatine in D dur. ms; 10 p. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Composer's name given as "Jos. Levi".
    - Leonard, Joseph. Passacaglia uber ein Thema von Rossi op. 8 no. 2. ms; 17 p. (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Complete title: "Passacaglia uber ein Thema von Rossi fur orgel fur Klavier zu vier Handen op. 8 no. 2".
    - Leonard, Joseph. Festival Prelude. ozalid; 2 p. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Leonard, Joseph. Processional on a Ground Bass. ozalid; 5 p. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Leonard, Joseph. [Music Notebook - Counterpoint]. 64 p. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Title on cover: "Kontrpunkt Notenheft I Joseph Levi U.3.17". Compositions for organ, string quartet, piano and 4-handed piano.
    - Leonard, Joseph. Processional for Organ. ozalid; 5 p. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Leonard, Joseph. In Memoriam. onionskin; ozalid; 3 p. (Box 3, Folder 2)
      "To the memory of my mother".
    - Leonard, Joseph. Prelude for Rosh Hashonoh. ozalid; 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Leonard, Joseph. Sabboth Idyll. ozalid; 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      "To Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco".
    - Leonard, Joseph. Elegie fur Violine/Sonatine in D dur. ms; 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Violin parts.
    - Leonard, Joseph. Eshet Chayil (A Woman of Valor). xerox; 3 p. (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Traditonal folk melody arranged by Joseph Leonard. arranged for cantor and choir.
    - Leonard, Joseph. Romanza. ozalid; spiral bound copy; 8 p. (Box 3, Folder 7)
      "A wedding gift to Eleanor and David". 7 items: 2 ozalids of score; spiral bound copy of score; individual parts for violin 1; violin 2; viola; cello.
    - Leonard, Joseph. Halo tsi vi seecho. ozalid; 3 p. (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Text from Joshua I: vs. 9.
    - Leonard, Joseph. With Love Everlasting. ozalid; 5 p. (Box 3, Folder 9)
      "To his friend Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco". M. J. J. copyist.
    - Leonard, Joseph. Melodie. ms; 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Leonard, Joseph. Lakol Seman. ms; 13 p. (Box 3, Folder 11)
      5 items: score; individual parts for violin 1; violin 2; viola; cello. Composer's name appears as "Joseph Levi".
    - Leonard, Joseph. Liturgical Compositions. spiral bound book of ms, ozalid, xeroxes; 152 pp. (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Leather and spiral bound book presented to Joseph Leonard on December 9, 1963, with typewritten and braille table of contents.
  - Music by Ernst Toch, Subseries 2.
    - Toch, Ernst. (Cadenza to Mozart Rondo). m; 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Toch, Ernst. Op. 74. ozalid; 39 p. (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Score for string quartet. Contains 3 movements.
    - Toch, Ernst. [Unidentified 3rd movement to string quartet]. ozalid; 4 p. (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Note in pencil at top: "This movement did not yet exist at the first performance and is therefore not in the recording". Possibly intended for Opus 74?
    - Toch, Ernst. Theme on Barbara. ms; 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 15)
      Contains theme and 3 variations. Full title: "Theme with missing variations to be added in birthday - installments until played for me by Barbara". Barbara is name of Alfred Leonard's daughter, with whom Toch shared same birthday date. Variation 2 dated December 7, 1946; untitled variation dated December 7, 1948.
    - Toch, Ernst. [Lullabies]. ms; 2 p. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Toch, Ernst. [Untitled work]. ms; 1 leaf; envelope. (Box 3, Folder 17)
      2 items: envelope with Ernst Toch return address to Barbara Leonard from Zurich; untitled piano ms signed by E. T., dated December 7, 1951.
  - Music by other composers, Subseries 3.
    - [Nolte?]. Mir folgen [?] schouslen. ms; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Originally located in folder with Joseph Leonard's compositions.
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus; Spiro, Mrs. Pinchas. [Song set to Alla Turca in honor of Joseph Leonard]. ms; 3 p. (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Song to commemorate Joseph Leonard's 10th anniversary directing and performing for Temple Beth Am, Los Angeles. Song text by Mrs. Spiro Pinchas.
- Correspondence, Series III.
  - P. Alfred Leonard and Ernst/Lilly Toch, Subseries 1.
    - Strecker, Willy. [Letter to Ernst Toch]. 1 leaf; note; xerox. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      3 items: typwritten letter from Willy Strecker to Ernst Toch in German dated Febrary 1, 1935; handwritten note attached to letter "The short story of the Second piano concerto"; xerox of January 1935 concert program listing Toch's 2nd piano concerto.
    - Toch, Lilly. [Letter to Alfred and Marjorie Leonard]. 2 leaves. (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Letter dated May 8, 1949 regarding trip back after visit with the Leonards.
    - Toch, Ernst. [Letter to Alfred and Marjorie Leonard]. 1 leaf. (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Letter thanking the Leonards for visit and gifts for trip back east.
    - Grenzebach, Herbert; Toch, Ernst. [Letters between Ernst Toch and Herbert Grenzebach]. 8 leaves. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Letters in German regarding recording with Telefunkenplatte GMBH.
    - Toch, Ernst; Toch, Lilly. [Letter to Alfred and Marjorie Leonard]. 2 leaves. (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Letter in German dated December 17, 1949 from Zurich, Switzerland.
    - Toch, Lilly. [Letter to Alfred Leonard]. 1 leaf. (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Letter in German dated March 27, 1950. Contains information regarding Telefunken and Capital Records; American Express address; concerts of Toch's piano concerto and quintet.
    - Toch, Lilly. [Letter to Alfred Leonard]. 1 leaf. (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Letter in German dated June 18, 1950. Contains information regarding performances of Toch's piano concerto; piano quintet; Telefunken recording of Pinocchio.
    - Toch, Ernst. [Letter to Leonard family]. 1 leaf. (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Letter dated December 15, 1950. Contains 2 inset photographs of Toch playing chess and Ernst and Lilly Toch on a pier. Information regarding "Dedication" piece originally intended for a daughter's wedding; completion of Symphony in 4 movements and upcoming premiere by Vienna Symphony orchestra.
    - Toch, Lilly. [Letter to Alfred Leonard]. 1 leaf. (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Letter dated May 14, 1951 in German. Contains information regarding recording with Klemperer; recordings of other composer's works.
    - Toch, Lilly; Toch, Ernst. [Letter to Leonard Family]. 1 leaf; airmail envelope. (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Letter dated August 29, 1952 to "quintet" regarding stay in Leonard's home. "The third symphony will be deeply rooted in your home" -Ernst.
    - Toch, Lilly; Toch, Ernst. [New Year's card to Leonards]. card; envelope. (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Card dated December 31, 1954. Contains short musical phrase with poem from Toch.
    - Leonard, Alfred. [Letter to Ernst and Lilly Toch]. 1 leaf; clippings. (Box 4, Folder 12)
      Typewritten onionskin copy of letter dated January 11, 1956 returning New Year's greetings. Reference to clippings to be passed on to Albert Goldberg. Clippings included with letter contains 3 reviews of Toch 3rd symphony dated December 3, 1955.
    - Toch, Lilly. [Letter to Alfred Leonard]. 2 leaves; magazine clipping. (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Letter in German dated December 7, 1959. Clipping entitled "Toch to Record Chamber Works for CR - Second Album Just Released."
    - Toch, Lilly; Toch, Ernst. [Letter to Alfred Leonard]. 1 leaf; airmail envelope. (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Letter in German dated October 1, 1960. Contains reference to St. Louis performance of Peter Pan and recordings.
    - Toch, Lilly. [Letter to Alfred Leonard]. 1 leaf. (Box 4, Folder 15)
      Letter in German dated November 24, 1960 regarding recording of quartet.
    - Toch, Lilly. [Letter to Alfred Leonard]. 1 leaf. (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Letter dated January 2, 1961. Contains concern regarding proposed birthday celebration of Toch to be organized by head of Affiliated Musicians.
    - Winston, Elizabeth; Toch, Lilly; Lieberson, Goddard; Toch, Ernst. [Letters regarding Columbia Records recording proposal]. 4 leaves. (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Contains 4 items: memo slip from Elizabeth Winston, received by Alfred Leonard dated October 5, 1961; Letter dated October 3, 1961 from Lilly Toch to Elizabeth Winston regarding Goddard Lieberson letter; letter dated September 13, 1961 from Goddard Lieberson of Columbia Records to Ernst Toch regarding recording of Toch's work in celebration of his 75th brithday; Letter dated September 16, 1961 from Ernst Toch to Goddard Lieberson expressing his wish to avoid duplication of previous recorded works.
    - Winston, Elizabeth; Toch, Lilly; Lieberson, Goddard; Toch, Ernst. [Letters regarding Columbia Records recording project]. 4 leaves. (Box 4, Folder 18)
      Contains 4 items: memo dated November 3, 1961 from Elizabeth Winston received by Alfred Leonard; letter dated October 28, 1961 from Lilly Toch to Elizabeth Winston regarding letters between Toch and Lieberson; copy of letter dated October 25, 1961 from Ernst Toch to Goddard Lieberson with list of previously recorded Toch works and suggestions for proposed Columbia recording; letter dated October 9, 1961 from Goddard Lieberson to Ernst Toch requestiong suggestions for smaller ensemble works to record.
    - Toch, Lilly. [Letter to Alfred Leonard]. 4 leaves; envelope. (Box 4, Folder 19)
      Letter in German dated November 30, 1961 with 3 page typewritten biography of Ernst Toch in English.
    - Toch, Lilly. [Letter to Alfred Leonard]. 1 leaf. (Box 4, Folder 20)
      Letter in German dated December 13, 1961 concerning Columbia recording.
    - Toch, Lilly. [Letter to Alfred Leonard]. 2 leaves; envelope. (Box 4, Folder 21)
      Letter in German dated December 14, 1961.
    - Toch, Lilly; Lieberson, Goddard; Toch, Ernst; Chapin, Schuyler. [Letters regarding Columbia Records recording project]. 8 leaves; 1 envelope. (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Contains 9 items: cover letter dated December 25, 1961 from Lilly Toch to Alfred Leonard in German; letter dated September 13, 1961 from Goddard Lieberson to Ernst Toch regarding proposal to record Toch's work in celebration of his 75th birthday; copy of letter dated September 16, 1961 from Ernst Toch to Goddard Lieberson with request to record previously unrecorded works; letter dated October 9, 1961 from Goddard Lieberson to Ernst Toch requesting further suggestions for recording project; letter dated October 17, 1961 from Ernst Toch to Goddard Lieberson acknowledging receipt of letter; copy of October 25, 1961 letter from Ernst Toch to Goddard Lieberson with list of previously recorded Toch works and suggestions for recording; letter dated December 6, 1961 from Schuyler Chapin suggesting recording Five Pieces and Sonatinnetta; letter dated December 20, 1961 from Ernst Toch to Schuyler Chapin approving project as proposed in December 6th letter; envelope dated December 26, 1961 from Toch.
    - Toch, Lilly; Steinberg, William. [Letters to Alfred Leonard; Lilly Toch; William Steinberg]. 3 leaves; 1 envelope. (Box 4, Folder 23)
      Contains 4 items: cover letter dated December 31, 1961 in German from Lilly Toch to Alfred Leonard; letter in German from Lilly Toch to William Steinberg dated November 30, 1961 regarding Ernst's 75th birthday and recording project; letter dated December 16, 1961 from William Steinberg, conductor of the Pittsburg Symphony to Lilly Toch promising to perform Toch's work in the following year and to propose recording of Toch's works to Command Records; envelope dated December 31, 1961.
    - Toch, Lilly; Toch, Ernst. [Letters to Alfred Leonard and Elizabeth Winston]. 2 leaves. (Box 4, Folder 24)
      Contains 2 items: letter dated December 30, 1961 from Lilly Toch to Alfred Leonard regarding list of performances of Toch's works; letter dated December 30, 1961 from [Ernst Toch?] to Elizabeth Winston regarding list of works [not included here] and photos to be sent.
    - Leonard, Alfred. [Letter to Lilly and Ernst Toch]. 1 leaf; 2 xeroxes. (Box 4, Folder 25)
      Letter dated April 28, 1962 expressing sorrow over news of Irving; report on wedding.
    - Toch, Lilly. [Letters to Alfred Leonard and Elizabeth Winston]. 2 leaves; envelope. (Box 4, Folder 26)